Comedian Chelsea Handler and former Israeli envoy Noah Tishby released a pro-Israel video today that
they said combats misinformation. I watched it and I found that it didn't combat much misinformation,
but it almost entirely was misinformation. Let's dive in. Progressives, especially on college
campuses and on social media, have been led to believe that any response by Israel to this
attack is unacceptable and to victim blame Israel for the entire situation to begin. Okay, no one
said that any response would be unacceptable. No one said that. There was obviously going to be a
response. The attack on October 7th was horrific and there were innocent hostages involved. If there
were special forces rescue missions, targeted attacks, if there was an acknowledgement that
the Israeli government had been rounding up Palestinians for a very long time, thousands
of them, and holding them without trial and maybe there should be a hostage swap to maintain the
sanctity of innocent life, there wouldn't be outrage like this. They've killed over 20,000 people
over 10,000 children. They've bombed refugee camps and hospitals. They told people to flee to a
region, that that region would be safe, and then they bombed it. They've killed aid workers and
journalists. The problem is not that there was a response. The problem is that the response has been
genocidal. Now, in terms of the victim blaming, it is not victim blaming to state that this is all part
of a longer story of occupation, oppression and violence. It is in no way justifying the October
7th attacks to put them in context. That is not victim blaming. I don't understand because
progressives should love Israel. Israel is a single consistent democracy and the only
progressive country in the entire region. Is it though? Can a democracy be a multi-tiered society,
an apartheid state? Can a democracy be an ethno state? Can a democracy be all but defined by a brutal
military occupation? Many would say no. Palestinians in the West Bank and Gaza do not have the same
rights and freedoms of Israelis, not even close. They do not have freedom of speech or assembly or
expression or movement. It goes as deep as different license plates and different roads. It is a democracy
for some, but a democracy for some is not a democracy. Do you like free speech? I like it. Being able to
criticize the government. Do you like that part? You can do that in Israel. Interesting. How about
Military Order 101, which states any Palestinian, and there are over 3 million living in the occupied
territories, who holds a gathering of more than 10 people that can be deemed as political by the
Israeli military is illegal and punishable by up to 10 years in prison. Is that the free speech
you're talking about? Is that the freedom of being able to criticize your government? Oh wait,
they're not their government. They didn't vote for them or elect them in any way, and yet
they still control many aspects of their lives. Also, what about this? What about the wide reports
that Israel is locking people in prison for social media posts? Is that the freedom you're
bragging about? And do you like gay weddings? You know the fun kind without straight people?
So does Israel. Gay marriage is not legal in Israel. It's not. You can have a gay marriage
there, but they won't recognize it as one. They do recognize same sex marriages performed elsewhere,
but in Israel? Nope. Now is Israel more progressive on these issues than nearby countries? Yes,
but this is brazen, unsuccessful pinkwashing, and it should be dismissed for the nonsense that it is.
Israel is our greatest defense in the Middle East for all of Western democracy and Western values.
If Israel goes down, guess who they're coming for next? What does this mean? Who's they? This
honestly feels like Trump level Western nationalist isolationist nonsense. And I need to say one more
thing just regarding their whole tone, this light, jovial, airy tone. When you take into account that
they are using that tone to defend a government that has killed over 20,000 people, over 10,000
children, that has bombed refugee camps and hospitals and ambulances, that has left over 2 million people
without a home, that has been dropping 50% unguided missiles wherever the fuck they want, that are
committing genocide on people that they have trapped. When you take all that into account, this video
should absolutely infuriate you. None of this is cute or sweet. Children are being bombed by the people
you are defending while you are making this video defending them.